Cool, so we're making some good progress.
We've added the rigid body to the player
so we can use forces, swing press play, our
player flies all the way into the air
and then drops all the way back down.
Now we're gonna make
it so we can use input
from the player to
actually control this jump.
So if we go back into
our player controller
script, we're going to go
into our update method
and we're going to use an if statement and
in that if statement we're going to check
whenever the player
presses the space bars
and then inside of our
if statement, now what
we're actually going to do is we're just
going to take our add force, cut it out of
start so that way
the player doesn't just
jump when it starts, although we
could do that because that'd be fun.
And in our if statement
we'll make it so that
the player jumps
whenever we press space.
Now one slight change
that we can make to
this to make it a lot
more immediate when the
player jumps is by actually changing
our add force method just a little bit.
So we're going to drop this back
down to 100, we'll say maybe 10 for now.
So you can see when we were originally passing
in this parameter, we were just passing
in a vector three, but you
can see when we added
this comma that we can
actually add in a force mode.
And so we can actually apply
different forces through this force mode.
So in fact, if we actually
type in, oh, it auto
completes force mode
for us, which is pretty nice.
So we'll just type force mode.
And then we're actually
going to apply an impulse force.
Now there's four different kinds
of forces that you can apply.
There's a normal force force mode,
which applies that force over time.
And this case force mode impulse immediately
applies the force that we want to apply.
So in this case, you should see that
player jump happen a little bit faster.
So if we go back
into unity, if we go to
our player and we focus on
them, and then we play our game.
Now when we press space, you can see
that the player jumps almost immediately.
And we in fact actually
need less force because
we're not trying to
apply a force over time.
We're just applying that force right now.
So immediately they get to 10.
So what you're going to
do is you're going to add
in your own if statement
to get the space bar input.
And then you're going
to move that add force
method from start down into our
update method inside the if statement.
And you're going to
change the parameters
that you're putting in so that
it's a vector 3 up times 10.
And you're applying the
force mode as an impulse.
Now it's your turn.